ALEX JIN

Senior Full Stack and Blockchain Developer

@ alex.jin220@gmail.com

https://github.com/silver-it

9 Singapore



SUMMARY

Organized, collaborative, and highly skilled full stack developer with 6+ years of professional experience in dynamic and deadline-driven work environments. Self-motivated and self-taught professional who likes to solve problems.

My repertory includes programming languages and tools such as ReactJS, Angular, VueJS, NodeJS, Laravel, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Gulp, SASS, LESS, theming with Material UI and Bootstrap, Apache and Nginx server configuration and more related to the Blockchain industry such as Solidity, Ethereum, Smart Contract, DeFi, NFT marketplace, Rust, Solana...

TECH STACK

Libraries and Frameworks

Javascript	Typescri	ot ReactJS	Angular	VueJS	NodeJS	Larav	el Python	ASP.NET	
React-Nati	ve Ionic	NativeScri	ot Flutte	r Rxjs	Redux	NgRx	Saga/Thunk	CSS	scss
Jasmine	Karma	Puppeteer	Solidity	Smart Cont	ract De	eFi Rus	st Solana	C/C++	

Database

MySQL M	longoDB	PostgreSQL	Firebase	AWS RDS
---------	---------	------------	----------	---------

Tools

Git	DevOps	Heroku	AWS	Npm	Gulp	Rest APIs	Apache	Nginx	Truffle	Hardhat
-----	--------	--------	-----	-----	------	-----------	--------	-------	---------	---------

EDUCATION

2009 - 2013

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science
Tsinghua University
GPA 6 / 6

WHAT I'M PROUD OF



My Courage

To always leave my comfort zone. I'm not afraid to do whatever I need to do to achieve my goals!



Keeping Good Relationship

I like to be a right-hand man regarding all the aspects.



My Focus & Persistence

Despite any hard situation, I keep my focus on my goals and always move towards them.



Massless Corp 5812 Geary Blvd, San Francisco, CA 94121, USA

email: richard@massless.io

To whom it may concern,

I recommend Alex Jin for the role of Web3 developer specialising in Smart Contract and Backend API development. His role at Massless Corp. was full time, fully remote and he reported to me, the Web3 Lead, directly.

He is up-to-date with the latest advancements in EVM technology which powers his clean and innovative code on projects. His work requires little oversight and is always happy to receive feedback. Whilst an employee at Massless he has communicated solo research projects, been involved with mainnet deployment of customer contracts and created experimental smart contracts to test concepts and potential exploits. He has excellent problem solving skills, writes neat efficient code in Solidity & TypeScript, and is able to integrate any library or 3rd party service we throw at him at the drop of a hat.

He always delivers high quality results on time and his written and verbal English communication skills are good.

Alex has been a great benefit to Massless and despite our differences in time zone (GMT+1 & GMT +8), he was very personable and communicative. He comes highly recommended.

All the best,

Richard Casemore

Massless, Web3 Lead email: richard@massless.io

EXPERIENCE

03/2022 - 10/2022

Senior Web3 Developer

Remote

Massless

Massless is an NFT Platform and Launch Partner. Massless provides an end-to-end solution for launching NFTs and creating Web3 experiences. Since August, 2022 Massless is providing a service to help investors and film makers. Browse vetted film investment opportunities from word-class producers. Open to accredited investors through Regulation D. Invest. Fund through fiat or crypto.

- Created smart contracts for ERC721, ERC721A, ERC1155 based NFT collections
- · Contributed Massless infrastructure web3 library "Smart Contract Library"
- Made frontend and backend API servers for NFT drops working on CI/CD with Google Cloud Platform and Vercel
- · Contributed Jungle Freaks Genesis, Fallout Freaks, Fallout Crystal NFT collection drops
- Contributed Angry Ape Army, Angry Ape Army Evolution, Angry Ape Army Valkyries, Spirit Apes, Angry Ape Armory NFT collection drops
- · Contributed to the smart contract development for decentralized studio
- Created Contract Interaction Tool which helps people to contract on-chain contract with it's address and ABI
- · Created Snapshot server to make snapshot smart contract state at a specified block number
- Contributed to Smart Contract Builder which creates smart contracts for different types of NFT collections just like OpenSea Wizard

08/2021 - 01/2022

Senior Javascript Engineer

Remote

Bright Data

Bright Data Inc is the world's #1 web data platform. Fortune 500 companies, academic institutions and small businesses all rely on Bright Data's solutions to retrieve crucial public web data in the most efficient, reliable and flexible way, so they can research, monitor, analyze data, and make better decisions.

It's platform is used worldwide by 15,000+ customers in nearly every industry. Their users love them because they provide customers with a cost-effective way to perform fast and stable public web data collection at scale, effortless conversion of unstructured data into structured data and superior customer experience, while being fully transparent and compliant.

They believe that making public web data easily accessible is essential to keeping markets openly competitive, benefiting all of them.

- Contributed to SERP(Search Engine Result Page) program and speed up the runtime for each request
- · Setup development pipeline inside LXC and worked thru it
- ${}^{\:\raisebox{3.5pt}{\text{\circle*{1.5}}}}$ Worked using CVS(Concurrent Versions System) as a version controlling system
- · Mainly worked in Ubuntu terminal and pure Javascript, additinally React.js library

02/2021 - 09/2021

Senior Blockchain Developer

Remote

Nifty Gateway

 ${\cal O}$ https://niftygateway.com/

Nifty Gateway is a digital art online auction platform for non-fungible token art founded by Duncan and Griffin Cock Foster, and has since been acquired by the Winklevoss twins. Nifty Gateway has sold NFTs by Beeple, Grimes, LOGIK and other widely followed NFT artists.

- Built one of the biggest NFT Marketplace of digital art on Ethereum network using ERC-721 for single and ERC-1155 for multi NFT.
- Developed whole smart contracts from scratch and past the Audit from SlowMist.
- Built token bridge between Ethereum and Binance so that users are able to migrate their NFTs from BSC to our platform.
- Implemented basic functionalities of NFT marketplace such as sale, auction, airdrop and used proxy for service fee calculation.
- Implemented NFT fractionalization so that users are able to co-won NFT and decide further steps like sale, auction, airdrop together.
- Key Achievements: NFT Sale, Airdrop, Service Fee, Auction, NFT Fractionalize, NFT Bridge, Governance

EXPERIENCE

10/2019 - 08/2020

Lead Software Engineer

Remote

Sitebubo

Sitebubo is a cloud-based website monitoring software provider. It offers features such as monitoring dashboard overviews, automated regulatory monitoring checks, regulatory health checks, uptime monitoring, security monitoring, conversation rate capturing, site speed check, SEO health checks, timely reports generation, and server monitoring. The company allows users to download its application on iOS and Android platforms.

- · Lead a team of 5 front end developers, giving support to the client's multi-cultural team, providing feedback, clarifying requirements and helping with technical questions
- Kept the Project Manager and the IT Leads updated on the overall progress of the projects and managed the tasks distributed to the team
- Upgraded Ionic v3 to v4.0
- Built stable and maintainable codebases
- Installed Bitrise CI/CD framework for Ionic v4.0 project
- Setup and managed API server, monitoring server, and load balancers

04/2019 - 09/2020

Full Stack Web Developer

Remote

Tensail Analytics

Tensail Analytics provides clients with unprecedented gaming industry expertise combined with a comprehensive customer-focused vision. The combination of the two is unmatched within the gaming service provider marketplace.

- · Scraped details of sports events, odds, boxscores, match stats, leaderboards from espn, rivals, synergy, stats-ncaa, donbest, pgatour and more
- Analysed the data contents and made expectation for the future match results
- Provided expectations with several formats according to the license
- · Kept managing the unmanaged VPS server

12/2018 - 04/2019

React-Native Developer

Malaysia

PetBacker

https://www.petbacker.com/

PetBacker connects loving dog walkers, sitters, boarding & groomers with pet owners just like you in all major cities & can help you get a loving trusted Pet sitter who could board your dogs & cats in moments after you make a request.

- · Used my extensive experience with front end and mobile development to define the structure and components for the project, making sure they are reusable
- · Kept the code quality high reviewing code from other developers and suggesting improvements
- · Interacted with the designer to suggest changes and to make sure the view he had about the design was translated into actual functionality

11/2015 - 12/2018

Fullstack Developer

Remote

Toptal

Toptal is an exclusive network of the top freelance software developers, designers, finance experts, product managers, and project managers in the world. Top companies hire Toptal freelancers for their most important projects.

- SPA development
- Building stable and maintainable codebases using ReactJS and Angular
- Design easy user interfaces and great user experiences for the digital platforms of small
- · E-commerce development with Shopify, customizing preexisting themes
- · Integrated external services such as AWS, Google API, cloud services, payment services and delivery, etc
- VPS configuration and optimization (Apache and Nginx)
- Created chrome extensions for the different purposes such as helping wholesale, time tracking, searching by keywords in different search engines, video downloading...